Sam Mans

Email: smans.tech@gmail.com
My Portfolio | GitHub | Linkedin

About Me

A Software Engineer with experience supporting enterprise, mobile, and web-based applications

Skills and Tools

Web Development

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Node, NgRx, Jasmine/Karma, SCSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, MongoDB, GIT

Services

GitHub, BitBucket, AWS EC2, CloudWatch, Jenkins CI/CD, Google Analytics, Mailchimp

Software

VSCode, Intellij, SourceTree, PgAdmin, SQLite, Spring Tool Suite, Redux Devtools, Postman

Workflow

JIRA, Slack, Basecamp, Microsoft Teams, Zoom, Agile Development

Relevant Work Experience

Software Engineer, Akamai Technologies

(July 2021 to Present)

- Working as part of Akamai's global UI Engineering team, collaborating with teams around the world
- Building and maintaining multiple applications used by Akamai internal and external customers
- Actively engaging with teams during ongoing technical work to promote collaboration
- Migrating legacy AngularJS applications to the latest version of the Angular framework

Angular 11+ | Angular JS | Node JS | Jasmine / Karma | CI/CD | i18n Internationalization | Black Duck

Software Engineer, Depository Trust & Clearing Corporation

(November 2019 to July 2021)

- Working as part of the <u>DTCC</u> Institutional Trade Processing unit's application development team
- Contributing to DTCC's shared component and capability libraries built with Angular 9
- Leading weekly UI cross-team meetings to coordinate efforts and updates to shared libraries
- Working with backend engineers to define requirements and coordinate changes to services and APIs

Angular 9+ | NgRx | Jasmine/Karma | Bitbucket | JIRA | Jenkins CI/CD | CloudWatch | EC2 | Maven

Web Developer, RBKJ

(September 2017 to October 2019)

- Working in web development and marketing for RBKJ on <u>Syyrup</u>, a positive news application
- Working with the lead developer and product team to improve the application, create content, measure performance, design promotional material, and manage social media activity
- Coordinating updates to the application and social media efforts with remote team members

Angular 2+ | Ionic | Firebase | GitHub | Analytics | Social Media | Digital Marketing

Education, Certifications and Coursework

B.S.B.A Marketing — Suffolk University, Boston, MA

- Concentration in Marketing and Information Systems Management